BU Records: Baylor Sheet Music collection, Inclusive: 1891-1941, undated
Baylor University, The Texas Collection
BU Records: Baylor Sheet Music collection
Inclusive: 1891-1941, undated
Baylor University, The Texas Collection http://www.baylor.edu/lib/texas/
BU/396
Uncatalogued Holdings, Texas Collection
1 OVZ box.
The Baylor Sheet Music collection is an assortment of songs directly related to events, traditions, and athletics at Baylor University.
Administrative Information
Physical Description
General condition: Poor.
Biography/Profile
BU Records: Baylor Sheet Music collection is an artificial collection created by The Texas Collection staff from different donors over time. The songs in this collection relate to events, athletics, campus, students, and traditions surrounding Baylor University. Many of the songs in this collection are still sung at various Baylor events. Some songs were written by people affiliated with Baylor, including staff and faculty members, such as Lily Russell.
Scope and Content
BU Records: Baylor Sheet Music collection is an artificial collection created by The Texas Collection from different gifts and purchases. The contents of the collection cover a span of fifty years, starting in 1891, and also includes undated pieces.
Series I. Composition is the only series in this collection. It contains sheet music and some informational documents regarding the history of certain songs that pertain to Baylor University. There are also songs that do not directly relate to Baylor but are dedicated to Baylor by the composer. The materials in this collection are in poor to average condition.
Arrangement
Prior to current processing, this collection's contents were organized in folders by song title. Those folders were not arranged in any particular order. No series were present and there were no prior inventories or supporting documents. At one point, the sheet music in this collection was part of the Texas Sheet Music collection, a separate artificial collection.
The collection is now arranged in one series, I. Compositions. The folders are arranged alphabetically by song title.
Access Restrictions
All requests for copying of materials must be submitted to The Texas Collection in writing. Please use the Request Form for Copying Materials sheet. Unpublished materials authored or otherwise produced by the creator (s) of this collection are in the public domain. There are no restrictions on use. Copyright status for other collection materials is unknown. Transmission or reproduction of materials protected by U.S. Copyright Law (Title 17, U.S.C.) beyond that allowed by fair use requires the written permission of the copyright owners. Works not in the public domain cannot be commercially exploited without permission of the copyright owners. Responsibility for any use rests exclusively with the user.
Acquisition Information
Accession No. BU/396.
Related Resources
Items in related collections
Texas Sheet Music collection, Inclusive: 1836-1979, undated
Roxy Harriette Grove papers, Inclusive: 1906-1953, undated, Bulk: 1930-1949, undated
Dorothy Scarborough papers, Inclusive: 1886-1938, undated, Bulk: 1923-1935
Lily McIlroy Russell papers, Inclusive: 1897-1968; Bulk: 1942-1958
Claude Eager Johnson
F. Arthur Johnson Papers, 1920-1971
Index Terms
Subjects (Organizations)
Baylor University -- Songs and music.
Subjects
Alma maters (Songs) -- Texas -- Waco -- Specimens.; Band music -- Texas -- Waco -- Specimens.
- Compositions, 1891-1941, undated; 1
  Administrative Information
  Physical Description
  General condition: Poor.
  Biography/Profile
  Series I. Compositions contains sheet music related to Baylor University. The main theme of the materials relates to events, traditions, and athletics at Baylor University. There are also songs that do not directly relate to Baylor but are dedicated to Baylor by the composer. The materials in this series are in poor to average condition.
  - “Alma Mater”: By Roxy Grove, undated (Box 1 OVZ, Folder 1)
  - “Baylor”: By Dorothy Scarborough and F. Arthur Johnson, 1910 (Box 1 OVZ, Folder 2)
  - “The Baylor Bears”: By Will N. Payne, undated (Box 1 OVZ, Folder 3)
  - “Baylor Ceremonial”: By Lily M. Russell, 1929 (Box 1 OVZ, Folder 3)
  - “Baylor Dear Baylor of Mine”: By Florence O’Brien Powell, 1920 (Box 1 OVZ, Folder 5)
  - “Baylor Fight Song”, undated (Box 1 OVZ, Folder 6)
  - “Baylor Forevermore”: By Claude Eager Johnson, undated (Box 1 OVZ, Folder 7)
  - "Baylor March for Pianoforte" by Rudolph Hoffman, 1900 (Folder 8)
  - “Baylor ‘U’”: By Joseph H. Burt, David Unruh, and Ivan Skougaard, undated (Box 1 OVZ, Folder 9)
  - “Bear Down Baylor Bears” By Fred Waring and Pat Ballard, 1941 (Box 1 OVZ, Folder 10)
  - “Cross Over The Bridge”: By Marie Abel, Jack Dillard, and Penny Edens, undated (Box 1 OVZ, Folder 11)
  - "The Holly Oak Grand Waltz" by F. W. Smith, undated (Box 1 OVZ, Folder 12)
  - “New Fight Song”: By Frank Boggs and Dick Baker, 1891 (Box 1 OVZ, Folder 13)
  - “The New Song”: By J. H. Luther and Geo. H. Rowe, undated (Box 1 OVZ, Folder 14)
  - “Oh Baylor, Bear On”: By Irl I. Allison, 1924 (Box 1 OVZ, Folder 15)
  - “Old Baylor is Marching”: By Dorothy Moore, 1928 (Box 1 OVZ, Folder 16)
  - “Our Baylor”: By Julian Edwards, undated (Box 1 OVZ, Folder 17)
  - “Ring Out” music, undated (Box 1 OVZ, Folder 18)
  - “Round ‘Em Up”: By Roxy Grove, undated (Box 1 OVZ, Folder 19)
  - “Pro Eccelsia, Pro Texana”: By Lily M. Russell, undated (Box 1 OVZ, Folder 20)
  - “That Good Old Baylor Line”: By Enid Eastland Markham and Jack Goode, undated (Box 1 OVZ, Folder 21)